A Guide to the Anna Whitehead Kenney Papers, 1965-1972
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Anna Whitehead Kenney Papers, 1965-1972
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1991-022
0.6 cu. ft. 2 boxes
The Anna Whitehead Kenney Papers contains a collection of biographical information about local families compiled by Kenney during her time as a curator at Smithfield Plantation.
Kenney, Anna Whitehead
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Anna Whitehead Kenney Papers were donated to Special Collections prior to 1992.
Biographical Note
Anna Whitehead Kenney was a resident of Blacksburg, Virginia and curator of Smithfield Plantation from 1965 to 1972.
Scope and Content Note
Papers consist of the files Kenney created while she worked at Smithfield, with historical and biographical information about the Preston family and other pioneer families of Blacksburg.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Special Collections is home to several collections relating to branches of the Preston family from Blacksburg, Montgomery County, and Abingdon, Virginia, including:
George Green Shackelford Papers, 1899-1990. Ms1983-008. Finding aid available online.
John Preston Deed, 1826. Ms2005-014.
John Preston Papers, 1806-1830, 1844, n.d. Ms94-034. Finding aid available online.
Preston Family (Alice Preston Moore Collection) Papers, 1745-1882. Ms62-004.
Preston Family (Charles Peale Didier Collection) Papers, 1747-1897. Ms85-020. Finding aid available online.
Robert Taylor Preston Papers, 1829-1871, n.d. Ms1992-003. Finding aid available online.
Smithfield Preston Foundation Papers, 1784-1881. Ms1997-002. Finding aid available online.
William Preston Land Grant, 1773. Ms94-027.
Willard Preston Genealogy, c.1998. Ms2009-121. Finding aid available online.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Preston family, Abingdon, Va.; Preston family, Montgomery County, Va.; Preston family, Solitude, Blacksburg, Va.
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); Smithfield Plantation House (Blacksburg, Va.)
Contents LIst
- Colonel James Patton--Immigrant (Box-folder 1-1)
- The Preston Family--Compiled By John Mason Brown 1870 Orlando Brown (Box-folder 1-2)
- John Preston--Immigrant (Came to America 1737; d. 1747; Burnkaneck (?) Elizabeth Patton Dec. 25 1700-Dec. 25-1776 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Colonel William Preston (1730-1783); Second Generation (Box-folder 1-4)
- Susanna Smith Preston (1793-1823) (Box-folder 1-5)
- Elizabeth Preston (1762-1779); M-Jan. 8 1779 to William Strother Madison (Box-folder 1-6)
- John W. Preston (1763-1827) "Greenfield", Third Generation (Box-folder 1-7)
- Francis Smith Preston (1765-1835); Aspenvale and Abingdon (Box-folder 1-8)
- Sarah Preston McDowell (1767-1841); Fourth Child of Col. William and Susannah; Born at Greenfield, May 3rd, 1767; Died July 3,1841 (Box-folder 1-9)
- William Preston, Jr. (1768-1821) of Kentucky; Third Generation (Box-folder 1-10)
- Nancy (Anne) Preston (1769-1782) (Box-folder 1-11)
- Susanna Preston (Born Oct. 4, 1772; Died June 21,1833) (Box-folder 1-12)
- James Patton Preston (1774-1843); Third Generation; "Smithfield" (Box-folder 1-13)
- Letitia Preston (1779-1852); Third Generation (Box-folder 1-14)
- Thomas Lewis Preston (1782-1813); Third Generation; Youngest Son of Col. William Preston (Box-folder 1-15)
- Margaret Brown Preston (1784-1843); "Peggy" (Box-folder 1-16)
- William Campbell Preston (1794-1860); Fourth Generation; Columbia, South Carolina (Box-folder 1-17)
- William Ballard Preston (1805-1862); Fourth Generation; "Smithfield" (Box-folder 1-18)
- Robert Taylor Preston (1809-1880); Fourth Generation; "Solitude" (Box-folder 1-19)
- John Smith Preston (1809-1881); Fourth Generation; Hampton-Preston House, Columbia, South Carolina (Box-folder 1-20)
- John Thomas Lewis Preston; B. 1811; Fourth Generation (Box-folder 1-21)
- Charles H. C. Preston; Fourth Generation; Son of Francis S. Preston (Box-folder 1-22)
- Thomas Lewis Preston; B. 1812; Fourth Generation; Son of Gen. Francis Preston and Sally Campbell (Box-folder 1-23)
- Elizabeth Randolph Preston; Fourth Generation; Married 1835 to William Armistead Cocke (Box-folder 1-24)
- William Preston III (1816-1887); Fourth Generation (Box-folder 1-25)
- James Francis Preston (1813-1862); Fourth Generation; "Whitehorn" (Box-folder 1-26)
- Hugh Caperton Preston (1856-1905_; Fifth Generation (Box-folder 1-28)
- William Redd Preston (1841-1872); Fifth Generation (Box-folder 1-29)
- James Patton Preston (d. 1911); Fifth Generation; Son of William Ballard Preston (Box-folder 1-30)
- James Patton Preston (1838-1901); Fifth Generation (Box-folder 1-31)
- William Ballard Preston (1858-1901); Fifth Generation (Box-folder 1-32)
- William Ballard Preston (1888-1959); Sixth Generation (Box-folder 1-34)
- Robert Baldwin Preston (1881-1944); Sixth Generation (Box-folder 1-35)
- Hugh Caperton Preston (1898-1966); Sixth Generation (File Empty) (Box-folder 1-36)
- Ellinor Graham Preston (Descended Through Mary Preston Howard and Cochran Preston Also); Sixth Generation (Box-folder 1-37)
- Preston Records (In Courthouse); Marriages, Births, Deaths; Wills, Deed; Plats in Montgomery County Courthouse) (Box-folder 1-38)
- Bibliography (Box-folder 1-39)
- Preston Cemetery At Smithfield (Box-folder 1-40)
- Smithfield Plantation--Photographs (Box-folder 1-41)
- Preston Brandy Warmer; Sold to Colonial Williamsburg 1942 by Mrs. Brockenborough Lamb, Sr. of Richmond, VA. Description and Records Enclosed; In Geddy Silver Shop (Box-folder 1-42)
- Hiram Powers (1805-1873)--Sculptor (Box-folder 1-43)
- Colonel John Floyd (1750-1783); Dr. John Floyd (son), Governor of VIrginia; John B. Floyd (Grandson), Governor of Virginia (Box-folder 2-1)
- Allied Families--Patton, Breckenridge, Floyd, Lewis, Smith, Madison Campbell, Howard, Brown, King, McDowell-Taylor-Thas. H. Benton(?); Contemporaries (Box-folder 2-2)
- Pioneer Stories (Box-folder 2-3)
- The Journal of Thomas Walker (Box-folder 2-4)
- The Southwest Corner By Goodridge Wilson (Box-folder 2-5)
- Kentucky Lands--Preston-Floyd, Breckenridge; Letters From Neal. O. Hammon, Louisville, Kentucky (Box-folder 2-6)
- History of Area--Newpaper Clippings (Box-folder 2-7)